A Guide to the Frederic Remington Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8242
Frederic Remington Collection 1888 -[ca. 1908]
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8242
16 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1966 Apr 4
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Frederic Remington to J[ospeh] H[enry] Harper, 1888 Oct 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Apologizes for seeming to be overly familiar, for having wrongly addressed him as "Mr. Harry Harper" before.]
  - Frederic Remington to Joseph Henry Harper, 1888 Nov 26; ALS, 2 p.
    [Outlines ideas for a magazine article on "Seats and Saddles" to be written by Captain [Joseph Haddox] Dorst and illustrated by Remington; mentions several "seats" to be included; mentions "Sketches in the Bridle Path Central Park," his most recent work for
    [Harper's] Weekly
    . ]
  - Frederic Remington to [Edward Windsor] Kemble, [ca. 188? -1892]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Writes that he would like him to meet Lieutenant Clark; invites him for dinner; sends love from [ Eva Caton Remington]; comments on his increased girth, which he illustrates.]
  - Frederic Remington to Joseph Henry Harper, [1898 Sep 16]; ALS, 2 p.
    [Suggests inclusion of his drawings, done for the
    [New York Morning] Journal
    in a proposed book on the Spanish-American War; writes that he is confident [William Randolph] Hearst will give permission; mentions [Robert Howard] Russell. ]
  - Frederic Remington to [Robert Howard] Russell, [1905-1906 Aug 28]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accompanies two drawings and manuscript No. 8 of
    The Way of the Indian
    , which would conclude the series.]
  - Frederic Remington to [Richard Harding] Davis, [ca. 1908] Aug 8; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks about the possibility of buying a farm in Westchester County, and who might give him "straight" information on the subject.]
  - Frederic Remington to Richard Harding Davis, [ca. 1908] Sep 24; ALS, 2 p.
    [Asks him to look at the [Barhite ?] place, fearing its low price might indicate an undesirable landscape; explains he cannot check it himself as he must finish an outdoor project before winter; mentions enclosing the "C & P letter."]
  - Frederic Remington to Richard Harding Davis, [ca. 1908]; ALS, 1 p.
    [Appreciates his "last call for diners in the dining car"; announces his purchase of a farm in Ridgefield, Connecticut. ]
  - Frederic Remington to Francis A. [Winship], Apr 19; ALS, 1 p.
    [Replies to inquiry about a new statuette; writes that three copies will be made but he must consult with the bronze founder before setting the price; mentions cire-perdue method of casting.]
  - Frederic Remington to [Riccardo] Bartelli, May 10; ALS, 2 p.
    [Advises arrangement of an exhibition of his bronzes and paintings in London; offers to pay expenses; writes that he has not heard from Philadelphia and his only "serious" plan at the moment is to recover from an attack of gout.]
  - Frederic Remington to Gilson Wilets, Jun 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Declines to have his "private life gone into publicly."]
  - Frederic Remington to Richard Harding Davis, [Jul] 28; ALS, 2 p.
    [Comments on Davis' article in
    Scribner's [Magazine]
    on San Juan Hill; mentions "old Casanova"; asks when he will receive Davis' book.]
  - Frederic Remington to "My Dear Judge", Aug 27; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accepts invitation to spend Sunday at Southampton; details his travel plans on the Long Island Railroad. ]
  - Frederic Remington to Professor [Julian Alden] Weir, Sunday; ALS, 1 p.
    [Recommends "Ned" Kemble, son of illustrator [Edward Windsor] Kemble, to the Yale Art School. ]
  - Frederic Remington to Robert Howard Russell, Friday; ALS, 1 p.
    [Writes that he is shipping 5 drawings and the manuscripts of 4 stories, to be followed next week by 4 more drawings.]
  - Frederic Remington to Norman L. Monroe, n. d.; ALS, 1 p.
    [Declines to write an article because of other commitments, but promises to communicate if he finds time in the future; quotes prices of $100 per thousand words and $150 per drawing, which is to be returned after use.]